

## Summary

I am a User Experience Designer with over eighteen years in digital design. As a User Experience Designer, my in-depth understanding of the design process allows me to meet user goals while balancing aesthetics and technical constraints. I design comprehensive design systems leveraging my extensive background in web design and development.

# Professional Experience

KBS

Associate Director, User Experience November 2016 – November 2017

- Designed a 3D cabinet configurator for Stanley Black & Decker. Created a design system, user flows, usability tests, and comprehensive prototypes
- Built a skills matrix for the UX team to help visualize strengths and gaps.
   Established a Sketch and InVision workflow to streamline work between the UX, Design, and Development departments
- Led a design discovery to redesign the PODS website. Delivered a UX audit, competitive research, personas, journey maps, and usability testing

#### **Senior User Experience Designer**

March 2015-November 2016

- I led the responsive redesign of BMWUSA.com. Built a modular design system, responsive grid, wireframes, user flows, and prototypes
- Redesigned the sign-up flows for the My BMW website. Created wireframes, user flows, interaction and technical documentation, and prototypes
- Designed a learning site for digital marketers at Hershey. Conducted user and stakeholder interviews, designed content types, and wireframes

### New York University

October 2008-March 2015

March 2015-November 2017

#### **User Experience Specialist**

Digital Communications Group, Information Technology Services August 2014–March 2015

- Designed and developed a new responsive user interface for Sakai—an open source Learning Management System. I wrote new HTML 5 templates and a Sass-based CSS framework. Incorporated the user experience and user interface improvements from NYU Classes
- Redesigned and prototyped a new user interface for NYU's Email Direct—a bulk email communication tool for NYU administrators

#### **User Experience Designer**

Academic Technology Services, Information Technology Services October 2011-August 2014

- Redesigned and developed a new user interface for NYU Classes—their Learning Management System (LMS). The redesign was based on extensive usability testing and research
- Created a 'Mobile First' prototype for our redesign of <u>MediaCommons</u>—a digital network for professors and post-graduate students of film and media studies
- Designed NYU Stream a video streaming service built on the Kaltura platform

### **UX/UI Skills**

- Design Systems, Style Guides, & Visual Design
- Responsive Web Design & User Interface Design
- Interaction Design & Information Architecture
- Sketching, Storyboarding, & Paper Prototyping
- Wireframing, Card Sorting, & High-fidelity Prototyping
- · Usability Testing, User Interviews, & Personas

#### Technical Skills

- · Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign
- · InVision, Principle, Framer, OmniGraffle
- · Final Cut Pro, Keynote, After Effects
- Markup (HTML) & Styling (CSS)
- · Sass, Javascript & ¡Query, Grunt & Gulp
- Git & SVN, PHP, MySQL, Drupal

#### **Interactive Designer and Developer**

Faculty Technology Services, Information Technology Services
October 2008–October 2011

- Designed and developed <u>MediaCommons—a digital network for professors and post-graduate students—using Drupal</u>. Established a distinctive look and feel for the <u>MediaCommons</u> network and its project sites
- Designed and developed two platforms for browsing the digital collections of *NYU Libraries*. Allowing patrons to view both image-based collections— scanned books and photographs—and stream audio and video collections
- Researched streaming services and wrote a report recommending the Kaltura platform for NYU's in-house streaming platform

### Columbia University

August 2001-September 2008

#### Senior Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures (a small 'digital agency' within Columbia University)

May 2005-September 2008

 Designed and developed educational course content and departmental websites for Columbia University and affiliated non-profits

#### **Web Designer and Developer**

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures August 2001–May 2005

- Worked with Columbia University faculty to design and develop interactive eseminars and courses
- Designed and developed interactive maps, audio slideshows, podcasts, and video production and post-production for streaming video and DVD

#### Scholastic

January 2000-May 2001

#### Web Designer

e-Scholastic

- Designed educational, commercial, and promotional websites for Scholastic
- Designed daily site graphics, interactive guizzes, and educational activities

# Teaching

**The New School**, Fall 2004–Spring 2008 Adjunct faculty member, *Media Studies* 

• Courses: Foundations of Media Design, Digital Video Effects, and Motion Graphics with After Effects

**Columbia University**, Summer 2005–Summer 2008 Instructor, *High School Program* 

• Course: Digital Filmmaking: From Initial Concept to Final Edit

# Education

1999–2007 **Ph.D. Media & Communication**, European Graduate School, Saas-Fee, Switzerland

1998-2001 Certificate in Film Production, The New School, New York, NY

1995-1996 M.Phil. Medieval History, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland

1991-1994 B.A. History and Philosophy, University College Dublin, Ireland

### Additional Information

### Organizations

- Co-Founder: NYU UX Group & NYU Web Designers and Developers Group
- Co-Organizer: DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 NYC Drupal Users Group
- Member: IxDA NYC UXPA Gotham Sass Meetup NYC Drupal Users Group Agile Experience Design Meetup Type Directors Club

# Selected Presentations, Event Organization, and Trainings

#### **Presentations**

- Better Tools for a Better Process at KBS' Bits & Bites 23rd March 2017
- Beyond Putting Lipstick on the Pig at EdUl 2014 30th September 2014
- Sakai: Meet MORPHEUS at Open Apereo 2014 2nd June 2014
- Rapid Prototyping Techniques at TorchTech: UX Networking Breakfast 23rd April 2014
- Fixing Broken User Experience at NYU ITS All Hands Meeting 21st September 2012
- MediaCommons 2.0 at Digital Library Federation Forum 5th May 2009

### **Event Organization**

- UX Networking Breakfast Co-Organizer TorchTech & NYU UX group 23rd April 2014
- UX @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 14th November 2013
- Usability @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 11th December 2012
- DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 Co-Organizer & Designer NYC Drupal Users Group June & December 2011

#### **Trainings**

- Design Teams Are a Design Exercise: How to Build, Inspire and Keep Design Teams (Happy) with Alberta Soranzo & Martina Hodges-Schell, Interaction 17 — February 2017
- Leading Creative Ideation with Christian Linsey & Jen Zhao, Cooper U May 2016
- Design Leadership with Teresa Brazen & Lane Halley, Cooper U August 2015
- Scaling User Interfaces with Amy Schade, Nielsen Norman Group August 2014
- UX Leadership with Kim Goodwin, Rosenfeld Media October 2012
- Do It Yourself Usability Testing with Steve Krug, Rosenfeld Media May 2012
- Sketching Interfaces with Jason Mesut & Sam Smith, Interaction 12 February 2012
- Mobile Prototyping Essentials with Rachel Hinman, Interaction 12 February 2012